

Enrique Alonso Argüelles

Junior Front-End Developer

Potsdam, Germany

enriquealonso608@hotmail.com

Profile

My name is Enrique Alonso Argüelles and for two years I work as a Junior Front-End Developer designing, developing and building responsive web apps.

I have a teachable attitude and a desire to learn. I am passionate, dedicated and eager to learn something new every day and I am always striving to bring 100% related to the work that I do.

I am good at working with other people and I enjoy working in teams. My passion as a programmer is JavaScript, together with React. I work every day with these technologies and I challenge myself to gain new knowledge and experience.

Currently, my main goals are to develop and implement high-quality component architectures that are stable, legible and extensible.

Therefore, I am looking forward to get the opportunity for a new challenge in my career.

Employment History

Sep 2017 — Apr 2020

Berlin

Junior Front-End Developer at cherryfish

I joined cherryfish in 2017 as they enter their final stages of turning a prototype into an MVP and be ready to hit the market.

- Bringing mockups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Building the app to responsive and usable.
- Monitoring website performance and rectifying front-end-related issues.
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub).
- Testing to identify bugs and technical issues before and after deploying.
- Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

Jan 2017 — Apr 2017

Jena

Temporary work at denn's Biomarkt

Support the store with preparing sale displays, ensuring the store is clean, stocking products, and processing customer orders.

2012 - 2013

Environment Artist at BrokenHead Studios

Madrid

Construction and design of aesthetically looking environment and scenes for a game or film.

Building anything from structures to terrain, or even environmental props.

Details

Potsdam, 14482, Germany

+49 160 6155536

Nationality

Spanish

Skills

React

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

Typescript

PostgresSQL

GraphQL

Knex.js

Jest

Languages

Spanish

English

• • • • • • •

German

Links

LinkedIn

Education

Apr 2017 — Jun 2017

,

Berlin

Spiced Academy

Coding Bootcamp where I gained deeper knowledge about coding and coded some projects.

- Gammers-Community- Web App where the users can log in and register, edit their profile and user profile pic and the username. The users can see how many friends they have and see who of their friends is online. They can also see the profile of other users and post comments in their profile. The users can chat in real-time in a chatroom.
- o React | NodeJs | Express.js | Axios| PostgreSQL | API | HTML | CSS | React-Bootstrap | Socket.io
- Petition Web App where the users can log in and register, sign a petition in a 2-D canvas, edit their profile and see other users who singed and filter them by city.
- o JavaScript | Canvas | NodeJs | Express.js | Jquery | PostgreSQL| HTML | CSS
- Imageboard Web App where the users upload an image, store it in a database, add Title, description and the author and after seeing all the image uploaded and search by author or title, see the image bigger, comment and delete the image.
 - o JavaScript | Angular | NodeJs | Express.js | Jquery | PostgresSQL | HTML | CSS
- Social Network- Web App similar to Facebook where the user can create a profile upload a profile pic, edit their bio, add friends and chat with a single friend or with several friends.
 - o JavaScript | React | NodeJs | Express.js | Axios | PostgreSQL | HTML | CSS
- Spotify-Search Web App using the Spotify API to search artists or Albums and display it on the screen.
 - o JavaScript | NodeJs | Express.js | Ajax | HTML | CSS
- Git Hub Search Web App using the GitHub API to search users and the repos of the user and display it on the screen.
- o JavaScript | NodeJs | Express.js | Ajax | HTML | CSS See less

Sep 2014 — Jul 2015

EF International Language Centers

San Francisco

Language Course

I spent a year in San Francisco, attending a language school to enhance my English skills.

Mar 2012 — Mar 2013

Centro de Formación CICE

Madrid

Profesional Master Visual Effects with 3D

2011 - 2012

Centro de Formación CICE

Madrid

Profesional Master animation and creation of videogames

2009 – 2011 CIFP Aviles

Aviles Specialist for the development of application program.

2004 – 2009 Colegio Paula Frassinetti

Aviles